<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jp</title>
    <link>https://jpsalo.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on jp</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://jpsalo.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://jpsalo.github.io/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jpsalo.github.io/project/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>me</title>
      <link>https://jpsalo.github.io/me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jpsalo.github.io/me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JP is a usability enthusiast who focuses on optimizing every aspect of product development, from the end user experience to the code architecture. Currently he is finding ways to create the best designer-developer handoff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JP is a programmer since 2010 and specialize in frontend development. He has solid, hands-on experience in product development for the web, backed by CS, HCI and cognitive science studies. JP strives for elegant and future-proof solutions which are both efficient and intuitive to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working at large and small companies and in projects of different scale and age has provided JP insight into team dynamics and business reasoning behind the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JP believes that the users of a service can&amp;rsquo;t be an afterthought—these people should be at the core of the work. He understands the value of a genuine connection with the users and knows that the best result is achieved when everyone is as close to the people as possible. He enjoys being part of the early-stage prototyping with pen and paper and gets most satisfaction from building complex glitch-free UIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JP specializes in User-Centered Design, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finding out people&amp;rsquo;s need with interviews and observation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prototype-oriented design and implementation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crafting, conducting and analysing usability studies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building interactive systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
