<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on jp</title>
    <link>https://jpsalo.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on jp</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://jpsalo.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stdy QRp</title>
      <link>https://jpsalo.github.io/project/stdy-qrp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jpsalo.github.io/project/stdy-qrp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout their studies, students may encounter problems in their courses where they need help from their teachers or from their peers but lectures and other contact teaching sessions can be at unsuitable times. Even though many courses have their own communication channels for seeking help, there are situations where the subjective experience of learning is better when done in collaboration with peers. This brings us to the three things needed for successfully studying together: shared location, time and a common subject. In this paper, we study how do we make it easy for students to arrange and participate impromptu study groups and present an application which combines space, time and problem into creating an ad hoc study group. Our testing concentrated on determining the best way for creator to communicate the subject of the group to other students in order to reach and match with as many potential peers as possible. Users were asked to use the application with two different interfaces and messages, and then fill in a survey about their experience. It was found that for the group creator, it is easier to express their problem in their own words, but group participants may find messages with predetermined and more generic subjects easier to understand and thus they are potentially more likely to participate in these study groups.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacker News Visualization</title>
      <link>https://jpsalo.github.io/project/hn-viz/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jpsalo.github.io/project/hn-viz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an interactive data visualization project with Hacker News data for discovering interesting stories. It shows 100 most voted and 100 most commented (duplicates removed) stories per each year in a bubble chart. Stories are divided in four category types: stories, jobs, projects (=show) and questions (=ask), and the bubble size is based on how many days was the discussion active. Contextual views show monthly statistics in bar charts, and also metadata of selected story with a link to the original thread in Hacker News. Application is here: hn-viz.herokuapp.com.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
