<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on jp</title>
    <link>https://jpsalo.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on jp</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://jpsalo.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stdy QRp</title>
      <link>https://jpsalo.github.io/project/stdy-qrp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jpsalo.github.io/project/stdy-qrp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout their studies, students may encounter problems in their courses where they need help from their teachers or from their peers but lectures and other contact teaching sessions can be at unsuitable times. Even though many courses have their own communication channels for seeking help, there are situations where the subjective experience of learning is better when done in collaboration with peers. This brings us to the three things needed for successfully studying together: shared location, time and a common subject. In this paper, we study how do we make it easy for students to arrange and participate impromptu study groups and present an application which combines space, time and problem into creating an ad hoc study group. Our testing concentrated on determining the best way for creator to communicate the subject of the group to other students in order to reach and match with as many potential peers as possible. Users were asked to use the application with two different interfaces and messages, and then fill in a survey about their experience. It was found that for the group creator, it is easier to express their problem in their own words, but group participants may find messages with predetermined and more generic subjects easier to understand and thus they are potentially more likely to participate in these study groups.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacker News Visualization</title>
      <link>https://jpsalo.github.io/project/hn-viz/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jpsalo.github.io/project/hn-viz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an interactive data visualization project with Hacker News data for discovering interesting stories. It shows 100 most voted and 100 most commented (duplicates removed) stories per each year in a bubble chart. Stories are divided in four category types: stories, jobs, projects (=show) and questions (=ask), and the bubble size is based on how many days was the discussion active. Contextual views show monthly statistics in bar charts, and also metadata of selected story with a link to the original thread in Hacker News. Application is here: hn-viz.herokuapp.com.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>extended mind</title>
      <link>https://jpsalo.github.io/project/em/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jpsalo.github.io/project/em/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You spend some of your best working hours focused on the software you use and not on the things you want to get done. Extended Mind provides a super simple, super fast, distraction-free replacement to cluttered office workflow tools. You can access Extended Mind from all of your devices to instantly manage your notes and tasks. This frees you to do what you do best: connect, create and collaborate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-extended-mind&#34;&gt;What is Extended Mind?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extended Mind is a minimalist, cross-platform, open source productivity service for note and task management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I use it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extended Mind gives you a place to store your private notes and tasks and to instantly access them using any of your devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To achieve super fast retrieving, Extended Mind gives tools to easily tag of notes and tasks, and also gives you instant full text search of all of your information. Instead of every single user coming up with their own tags, Extended Mind gives you a set of categories for items and also a set of well thought out public keywords.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extended Mind is free to use right away. You can try out the app without registration and later on sign up for a free account. Upgrading to the premium version of the Extended Mind let’s you simultaneously connect unlimited number of devices to your account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;innovativeness&#34;&gt;INNOVATIVENESS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most unique aspect of Extended Mind is the strong scientific background and respect for human biology and psychology of our team, which guides the development of the service. For the service to become a true extended mind, the time it takes to both retrieve and store information has to be on par with our biological memory. This is why minimalism pervades the entire service: every unnecessary visual element and shiny feature will be removed if it distracts the user from the cognitive task she wants to perform. The service will be built using tools that provide the very best performance with the least amount of code. Extended Mind will always be focused on content and making it as easy and fast as possible to use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another innovative feature of Extended Mind is the folderless storage of items. In Extended Mind every item can be grouped and associated to other items via a network of tags. Extended Mind gives you a set of well thought out categories and keywords that the user can start to use immediately, while still allowing the user the create her own tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, the open source implementation of the service is a strong signal to the users that their information will never be exploited. This differentiates Extended Mind from the vast majority of technology startups, and is a good fit for the scientific method and the open access and open data movements.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
